<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article xmlns="http://splitcells.net/sew.xsd">
    <!--
        SPDX-License-Identifier: EPL-2.0 OR GPL-2.0-or-later
        SPDX-FileCopyrightText: Contributors To The `net.splitcells.*` Projects
    -->
    <meta>
        <title>Aspects And Assumptions Relevant To This Attempt At Defining Intelligence</title>
    </meta>
    <chapter>
        <title>Aspects And Assumptions Relevant To This Attempt At Defining Intelligence
        </title>
        <chapter>
            <title>Turing Test: An Implicit Definition Of Intelligence
            </title>
            <paragraph>
                <link url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turing_test">
                    The Turing test
                </link>
                can be seen as an attempt to better understand intelligent behavior of humans.
                It does not try to define intelligent human behavior explicitly,
                nor does it state that human behavior is not dull.
                Instead, it defines a way to determine,
                if something is a human behavior or not.
                If human behavior is seen as inherently intelligent,
                then this test may be able to detect a subset of intelligent behaviour.
                It firstly isolates all important factors of the examined subject and
                secondly strictly states,
                which properties can be used in order to classify the subject.
                A downside of this approach is the fact,
                that not all intelligent human behavior can be classified as such,
                because biological processes are not considered.
                It is implied, that human in general are able to distinguish between human behavior and
                other behavior.
                The Turing test itself does not predict any concrete properties of humans or intelligence.
            </paragraph>
        </chapter>
        <chapter>
            <title>Global Versus Local Optimization</title>
            <paragraph>
                Requiring intelligence to do global optimization,
                does not seem to make sense,
                as it would otherwise mean,
                <link url="http://www.spektrum.de/kolumne/der-iq-reicht-nicht-mehr-aus/1502371">
                    that 2 instances of intelligence, are by definition not allowed to fight against each other.
                </link>
            </paragraph>
        </chapter>
        <chapter>
            <title>Emotional Intelligence</title>
            <paragraph>Emotional intelligence is not considered to be different to
                mathematical intelligence in this context.
                In this context it is assumed, that emotional intelligence,
                is intelligence applied to a subset of things.
            </paragraph>
        </chapter>
    </chapter>
</article>