<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns="http://splitcells.net/sew.xsd"
         xmlns:d="http://splitcells.net/den.xsd">
    <meta>
        <title>An Attempt At Defining Intelligence</title>
        <d:task>
            <d:todo xl:href="https://writing.stackexchange.com/questions/34783/writing-a-super-intelligent-ai">
                It may be important to have a will.
            </d:todo>
            <d:toDo>Is this relevant?
                <d:toDo xl:href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=szXf0VLuQLg"/>
                <d:toDo xl:href="https://medium.com/incerto/iq-is-largely-a-pseudoscientific-swindle-f131c101ba39"/>
            </d:toDo>
            <d:toDo>Could human rights be applicable for AI?</d:toDo>
        </d:task>
    </meta>
    <content>
        <paragraph>This article tries to forge a definition for intelligence.
            The background of the starting point for this attempt is computer science.
            The most important requirement for the definition is the maximization of its applicability.
        </paragraph>
        <chapter>
            <title>Aspects and Assumptions Relevant to This Attempt at Defining Intelligence
            </title>
            <chapter>
                <title>Turing Test: Implicit Definition of Intelligence
                </title>
                <paragraph>
                    <link>
                        <text>The Turing test</text>
                        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turing_test</url>
                    </link>
                    can be seen as part of an attempt at defining intelligent behavior of
                    humans. It
                    does not try to define intelligent human behavior
                    explicitly, nor does
                    it
                    state that human behavior is not dull. Instead, it defines a way to
                    determine, if something is a human behavior or
                    not. If human
                    behavior is
                    seen as inherently intelligent, then this test classifies a subset of
                    intelligent behaviour. It
                    firstly isolates
                    all important factors of the
                    examined object and secondly strictly states, which properties can be
                    used
                    in order to classify the examined
                    object in question. A downside of this
                    approach is
                    the fact, that not all intelligent human behavior can be classified as
                    such,
                    because
                    biological processes are not considered. The test classifies a
                    certain attribute of behavior based on an implicit definition. It
                    is
                    implied
                    that human in general are able to distinguish between human behavior
                    and
                    other behavior that differs from them in at least one relevant
                    property. The
                    Turing
                    test itself does not predict any concrete properties of the examined
                    thing.
                </paragraph>
            </chapter>
            <chapter>
                <title>Intelligence as Global Optimization Versus Local Optimization</title>
                <paragraph>
                    The (algorithmic) complexity of intelligence is an important property
                    in this context, as it seems to be seen by many people.
                    <link>
                        <text>The size and the number of optimized variables alone</text>
                        <url>http://www.spektrum.de/kolumne/der-iq-reicht-nicht-mehr-aus/1502371
                        </url>
                    </link>
                    are not assumed an important concern for the purpose of defining
                    the
                    properties of an intelligent process.
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph>
                    Additionally, in the real world global solutions doesn't seem to be possible as
                    the set of all variables is not know.
                </paragraph>
            </chapter>
            <chapter>
                <title>Emotional Intelligence</title>
                <paragraph>Emotional intelligence is not considered to be different to
                    a classical intelligence for the intelligence definition.
                    In this context it is assumed, that emotional intelligence,
                    is intelligence applied to a subset of things.
                </paragraph>
            </chapter>
        </chapter>
        <chapter>
            <title>Objectives of Defining Intelligence</title>
            <chapter>
                <title>Type Signature of an Intelligence Definition</title>
                <paragraph>Simply speaking, the aim of this definition is to
                    determine, if a
                    given process is intelligent or not. In this context, it is
                    assumed that
                    all aspects of a reviewed process are visible, in order to simplify the definition.
                    It is also assumed, that an instance of intelligence is equivalent to
                    an intelligent process. This in turns allows one to describe an data structure for intelligence.
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph>The formal type signature is:</paragraph>
                <list>
                    <item>Formally a process w is defined as a string of Σ, where Σ is an non empty alphabet:
                        <quote>w ∊ Σ</quote>.
                    </item>
                    <item>An intelligence definition is a classifier of any process w:
                        <quote>intelligent(w) = 1 if w is intelligent else 0</quote>
                    </item>
                </list>
                <chapter>
                    <title>Notes</title>
                    <d:toDo>Compare intelligence as event based history vs. intelligence as decision maker in a decision
                        tree
                        vs. intelligence as a string.
                    </d:toDo>
                </chapter>
            </chapter>
            <chapter>
                <title>Additional Intelligence Definition Implementation Requirements</title>
                <paragraph>The most important requirement to such an implementation
                    is, that it has to be useful.
                    It should not contradict other theories except for other intelligence definition.
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph>Such an implementation shall be useful at least for a
                    nonempty subset of all actors, who can benefit from intelligent process
                    identification.
                    In the ideal case this set should contain all such actors. An actor
                    finds it useful to identify intelligent processes, if a
                    cost free usage of
                    such a
                    definition has benefits for that actor. This implies that actors are
                    optimization systems.
                </paragraph>
                <d:todo>Formalize the maximization of the usefulness of the intelligence classification.</d:todo>
                <paragraph>The implementation shall have such a structure, that third
                    parties can be convinced, that the given construct in fact defines intelligence.
                </paragraph>
            </chapter>
            <chapter>
                <title>Objectives' Properties</title>
                <paragraph>
                    The aim of defining intelligence is not entirely objective. Also,
                    there is a formal and objective signature of an intelligence
                    definition, the additional implementation requirements require
                    an already present intelligence definition.
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph>The set of actors who can benefit from intelligent
                    process
                    identification, is also not completely documented in detail as it
                    also implicitly
                    depends on an already present intelligence definition.
                    This in turn could lead to a circular definition.
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph>The fact that such a definition has only
                    to be useful to a subset of actors, who can benefit from intelligent
                    process
                    identification, indicates that there are possibly a multitude of
                    intelligence definitions. This in turn indicates, that an intelligence
                    definition may be partially depended on the observer in question.
                </paragraph>
            </chapter>
        </chapter>
        <chapter>
            <title>Related Speculations</title>
            <paragraph>The possible relativity of intelligence may be related
                to the algorithmic complexity and
                the processing capabilities of the
                observer and its objects in
                question. This seems to be
                compatible to the observation, that it is hard to describe or understand
                intelligent behavior in detail. It
                may even explain, why a part of artificial intelligence development
                seems to be driven by gains
                in information
                processing efficiency as access to more capable
                hardware allows one to execute
                more
                complex algorithms.
            </paragraph>
        </chapter>
        <chapter>
            <title>An Intelligence Definition</title>
            <paragraph>An intelligence is defined via a classifier as this in accordance to the intelligence definition
                signature:
                <quote>intelligent(w) = 1 if w is a random optimization else 0</quote>.
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph>Randomness is defined in this context, as information/thing that is not accessible from the
                perspective of the actor. Note that this does not state, if there is indeterminism or not.
                This also does not state, that everything is deterministic.
                Neither does it state, why the information is not accessible.
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph>A random optimization is an optimization, where the objective/constraint is random.
                This means, that an actor is not able to determine the objective of an intelligence completely by
                definition.
                This also means, that intelligence is subjective by this definition.
            </paragraph>
            <d:toDo>Subjectivity as an parameter of the definition.</d:toDo>
            <d:toDo>Check requirments.</d:toDo>
            <d:toDo>Some things need to be done via intelligent beings.
                These requirements also define intelligence.
            </d:toDo>
            <d:toDo>Define effective intelligence.</d:toDo>
            <d:toDo>Define competitive intelligence.</d:toDo>
        </chapter>
        <chapter>
            <title>Conclusion</title>
            <d:toDo>The question of intelligence is irrelevant (i.e. autonomy, free will, politics already provide
                similar definitions)
                for most.
            </d:toDo>
        </chapter>
    </content>
</article>